Okay. So, what is the syntax of how you
create a promise? Well, the way you
create a promise is you use the keyword
new and then you say promise. And then
you're going to want to store that
promise in a variable. So, I'd say let
my var equal a new promise. If I do this
opening parenthesis, you'll see that it
says it takes an executor function. That
function takes in two parameters,
resolve and reject. Resolve is a
function that gets called and receives a
value for if the code successfully ran.
Um, think of the when I gave you ice
cream in the example before and reject
is what it will do if it didn't get back
what we expected. Um, for example, when
I gave you the broccoli. So, writing it
on multiple lines makes it helpful to
see how the syntax works. So, I'm going
to do that really quick. Um, so I'm
going to write my executor function
here. So, I'm going to say function
executor
and it takes in two parameters resolve
and reject. And these parameters are
automatically passed in. And then inside
we can call our function. So we could
say set timeout.
And we could set our timeout for um we
could call the resolve function inside
the timeout. And outside the timeout
um we can put 1,00 seconds. And if we
want the resolve function to return
hello world, let's say we want to return
hello world after this wait time of
1,000 milliseconds, then we would say k
inside of our timeout call the resolve
function after 1,00 milliseconds and to
the resolve pass hello world. We could
also use this reject function if our
code was going to fail. Um, our timeout
isn't going to fail, so I'm not going to
call reject right now. I'll show that in
a later video. But for now, this is how
you create the function that goes inside
of the promise. And then in the promise,
you pass that function. Now, some of you
may with sharp eyes may have noticed
that you could have probably simplified
this onto one line. The way you do that
is you'd say let promise equal and you
can say a new promise and into that
promise you pass a function that
receives resolve and reject.
And then
um it has a timeout inside of it. Um and
in that timeout it calls resolve
and passes hello world
and then we can have that pause for
thousand milliseconds. So this is the
same thing but instead of having to
create our executor function outside we
created it inside. And so that's how you
make a promise. But once you've made a
promise, how do you access it? What does
that even mean?